biztechconsultancy.com 2018-08-24

# Privacy Policy Under IT Act, 2000 & Amendment 2008 | Biztech Consulting & Solutions

Your Privacy is Important for Us

Biztech IT Consultancy Private Limited is committed to ensure that we serve you and your requirements in most efficient manner. And while doing so, we ensure that your privacy is well-protected. In order to ensure that we deliver our commitment, we keep transparent processes about the data we collect about you, how it is used and it is never shared with any third parties with or without our conscious efforts.

This Privacy Policy is applicable when you use our website, visit a live demonstration of the product on the website and query us using any of the forms on the website. While querying us for any of the products or services offered by Biztech IT Consultancy Private Limited, we seek your consent to allow us to communicate with you and share details as requested by you.

Introduction

Our users (“Members”) share details such as their name, email address, country, phone number, exchange knowledge and the nature of their requirements with us. This content and data is only viewable to our employees (“Team Members”).

We use the term “Listed Countries” to refer to countries in the European Union (EU), European Economic Area (EEA), and Switzerland.

Data Controllers and Contracting Parties

If you are a resident from any of the “Listed Countries” or anywhere across the globe, Biztech IT Consultancy Private Limited will be the controller of your personal data provided to, or collected by or for, or processed in connection with our Services; you are entering into the User Agreement with Biztech IT Consultancy Private Limited.

As a Member of our Services, the collection, use and sharing of your personal data is subject to this Privacy Policy and updates.

Change

Biztech IT Consultancy Private Limited (“we” or “us”) can modify this Privacy Policy, and if we make material changes to it, we will provide notice through our Services, or by other means, to provide you the opportunity to review the changes before they become effective. If you object to any changes, you may notify us through our website, email or phone call to unsubscribe you or to remove your personal data.

You acknowledge that your continued use of our Services after we publish or send a notice about our changes to this Privacy Policy means that the collection, use and sharing of your personal data is subject to the updated Privacy Policy.

1\. Data We Collect

1.1 Data You Provide to Us

You provide data when you (i) sign-up, (ii) purchase any of our products or services and/or (iii) share a query using any of the forms for our products or services.

This Data Includes

For activities (i) and (iii) listed above you share data including your name, email address, mobile number, password, country and domain or website name. If you are buying any of our products or services, you share all these details and also share your address of communication, billing information (e.g. credit card), and your store admin details for backend access. We never save your credit/debit card details.

2\. How We Use Your Data

We use your data through activity (i) and (iii) to fulfill your requirement through interacting with you to ensure your query is handled in the most efficient manner. Through activity (ii) we aim to provide products or services you ordered, provide support, personalize and develop our services to serve you better.

We never share your data with any third parties. In the event of having a local copy of your store for development purposes, we clean the data at regular intervals. In these specific instances we act as “Processors” for your end customers’ data.

3\. Choice/Opt-out

Once you are registered at the our site, you will have the option at any stage to inform us that you no longer wish to receive future services, e-mails and you may “Unsubscribe”, “Opt-Out” or by sending Unsubscribe Request on [unsubscribe@biztechcs.com](mailto:unsubscribe@biztechcs.com).

Further, as per Rule 5(7) of the Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 of Information Technology Act, 2000 amended through Information Technology Amendment Act, 2008, you have an option to withdraw your consent for use of your sensitive personal data given earlier to us. Such withdrawal of consent shall be sent in writing to our registered address.

4\. Reasonable Security Practices As per I.T.Act, 2000 and its Rules

We have implemented reasonable security practices as per Rule 8 of the Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 of Information Technology Act, 2000 amended through Information Technology Amendment Act, 2008.

We have implemented stringent, internationally acceptable standards of technology, managerial security, technical security, operational security and physical security in order to protect your personally identifiable information from loss, misuse, disclosure, alteration or destruction. The data resides behind a firewall, with access restricted to our authorized personnel only.

We have implemented “Reasonable Security Practices” as required by the Information Technology Act, 2000 rules including any amendment in the said Act and its rules. By complying with such provisions, We assure you proper care and control over our I.T. and Security operations as required under relevant sections mainly section 43, 43A, 45, 66,72A & 85 of I.T.Act, 2000 and I.T.A.A, 2008 including related rules and therefore you agree that we shall not be held responsible for any fraudulent/criminal activity with regards to your sensitive personal information stored in our website.

By using this website, you agree that we shall not be held responsible for any uncontrollable security attacks and in such cases, you agree that we shall not be held responsible for any type of financial losses, loss of opportunity, legal cost, attorney’s fees, business losses, reputation loss, direct and indirect losses that may occur to you as per the Provisions of Section 43, 43A and 45 of Information Technology Act, 2000 including any amendments in the said Act and any other laws of India for the time being in force.

You further agree that our management shall not be held responsible directly or indirectly for any cyber crime related criminal liabilities under I.T.Act,2000 relating to your information as you have agreed and acknowledged that our management complies with due diligence (care & controls) requirements of I.T.Act,2000 including its rules and amendments.

OUR REASONABLE SECURITY CONTROLS INCLUDE BUT NOT LIMITED TO FOLLOWING:

  1. Software Firewall
  2. HTTPS (SHA 256 bit encryption)
  3. Cyber Law & Security Compliance intimation letters to our team
  4. Cyber Law & Security Awareness for our team

Further, you also agree and acknowledge that our management shall never be held responsible regarding privacy of your sensitive personal data in case of sharing your sensitive personal data to any authorized cyber investigation agency of appropriate government authorities as required under sections 67C, 69, 69A, 69B, 70B, 79 and 80 of I.T.Act,2000 including its amendments and rules.

Grievance Redressal

If you have any questions or grievances regarding the privacy statement, practices of the site, or any other transaction issue, please contact our grievance officer on [grievance@biztechcs.com](mailto:grievance@biztechcs.com).

We have appointed our grievance officer as per Rule 5 (9) of the Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 of Information Technology Act, 2000 amended through

Information Technology Amendment Act, 2008 and you can contact us on above given email address.

Applicable Laws & Jurisdiction

You agree and acknowledge that this privacy policy agreement shall be governed by Laws of India without any conflict of laws. Further, you agree and acknowledge that Indian courts located in city of Ahmedabad , State of Gujarat shall have jurisdiction for any matters relating to this privacy policy. If you don’t agree then you shall not use this website.
